Hey, quick note. Today is Lauren's
birthday and Lauren asked me to make a
special bonus coupon for today only on
the courses on building your wealth and
the alpha membership at meetke.com. Also
works over at househack.com reinvest.
Check that out. I'd love to see you
there. Special bonus coupon expires
tonight at 11:59 p.m. In this video,
we're going to discuss the bifurcation
of artificial intelligence and what it
means for your portfolio. We'll talk
about some stocks to avoid and some
stocks that could be big beneficiaries
around this concept. But I really want
to use this video to explain this
concept of the bifurcation of artificial
intelligence. And while that sounds
complicated, it'll make a lot of sense
towards the end. Unfortunately though,
it does mean we have to start by talking
a little bit about Zuck. Yes, Mark
Zuckerberg. Because on well today Meta
announced that they're going to release
their more powerful than Meta Spark
model Muse Glimmer as an open weight
model. And this is pretty powerful
because it's coming at the same time as
Alibaba is releasing their Quen 3.8 27
billion parameter model this week. Zuck
is now taking the point of view that the
frontier or best quality LLMs shouldn't
just be built for the highest paying
companies or governments or
institutions. It should favor
individuals.
This is kind of the Elon Musk mission
with open AI. Elon Musk backed open AI
so that artificial intelligence would be
available for the people. And so it was
not on my bingo board to see Zuck kind
of take that lead, if you will. It's
possible that's happening because Meta
has been falling behind on their own
version of Frontier AI. So, it's kind of
easy to bag on the leaders and go, "Ah,
well, Frontier Labs and the leaders,
they're they're losers anyway. We we
want to give this to the masses." You
know, kind of convenient timing. But it
comes at the same time as there are some
serious concerns about the scurve issue
that anthropic and open AI face and that
is what sets up the bifurcation of AI
and it changes the way that we invest.
So in order to get this you have to know
that there are really two ways AI
funding gets spent. one is at the
frontier compute layer. This is and then
we'll talk about S-curves and that in
just a moment. This is where the
bifurcation starts. You've got on one
hand your frontier compute, your Vera
Rubin, so the Vera CPUs, the Reuben GPUs
together as a GB300, a fullscale
Blackwell cluster. You're spending
millions of dollars per rack for these,
somewhere around $4 million just for a
rack on these. Uh there's talk that
Jensen is trying to introduce these
models with various or these these racks
with different variations of memory. So
that way we could get away from some of
the most expensive AI uh memory clusters
and get to clusters that could
potentially perform just as well with
less memory. And maybe we could use less
memory because it's so expensive now and
use some CPO technology which is
basically fiber optics like what
Broadcom or Marll produce to make Vera
Rubin great without being an arm and a
leg in terms of cost because the
Frontier Labs only have a finite level
of money. Anthropic OpenAI plus the
Google or even the Microsofts, right?
There's a limit to how much money these
companies can realistically raise. And
the Frontier Labs
give Nvidia the highest margins
possible. Okay? Somebody buying a 5090
consumer grade GPU isn't giving Nvidia
the same margins as Elon Musk going,
"Bro, I'm gonna buy 200,000 GB300s,
please. Okay? Don't care what the price
is. I'm a trillionaire."
Right? Like so on that's one hand right
frontier compute. Okay this is where
like do you know what Microsoft just
pulled off? Microsoft literally just
changed their depreciation schedule from
15 years to 25 years. They did that
because now all of their leases for
offices and data centers are getting
reclassified as an operating expense or
a cost of goods sold rather than a
capex.
That's because right now a lot of
executives know if you show high capex
because you're spending so much money on
these Nvidia chips, your stock could go
down, man. You know, you're getting
punished because the capex is too much.
Google raises money. Google's been off
alltime highs. They've been suffering
because they're coming out with a big
sucking. Oh, we need we're going to sell
$40 billion worth of stock. We haven't
sold any of those yet as of June 30th.
So, we still got to sell that. Maybe
they've been selling here recently. They
also raised money from uh Birkshire
Hathaway and another about $25 billion
on top of that. So, you know, there's
some real money raised going on. But the
point is that's going into the main
frontier compute side of this this two
factored story. High margins, big
systems, big racks, expensive. It's for
the big boys with the big money. And
this is why Jensen cozies up to Elon,
baby. Okay. Then you have the second
side of the market. The second side,
this is the bifurcation, right? Split
the cataclysm for those World of
Warcraft folks. Okay. Then you got the
inference and the fine-tuning side. So
big models think massive pre-training,
some post-training, massive expensive
data sets and um uh and and obviously
therefore they need these massive
servers and data centers. Then you get
the enterprise AI side. This is kind of
like where, in my opinion, our company
sits along with, frankly, 90% of real
world AI.
Totally fine to use openweight models.
You're not trying to create the next
greatest LLM. You're trying to use the
cheapest LLM possible to make the most
freaking money possible. And this is why
5090s from Nvidia have doubled in price.
This is why the RTX 6000 Blackwell chip
has doubled in price. Reinvest owns both
of those. But the reality is we can get
90% of Frontier well quality and and
frankly you know we're maybe three
months behind Frontier LLMs in and when
I say we I mean like all enterprise AI
that's running on local AI systems.
You're maybe 90% of the way to frontier
quality. And I use that on a time basis.
Maybe we're 3 months behind is what our
dev team thinks in terms of how far
enterprise AI is behind the frontier
labs. So those big spenders are here and
you know most enterprise and businesses
are like maybe three months behind
because of the benefits of openw weight
models which if you're three months
behind and you know this AI boom's been
going on for about 36 months maybe a
little bit more closer to 40 months
you're really only time-wise 10% behind
you're 90% caught up that's my point so
the businesses using Blackwell RTX 6000s
which run for about $18,000 or 5090s
which you know run for somewhere around
4,900 bucks now unless you buy them in
bulk.
People are able to get a massive leap
towards frontier quality on consumer
grade chips or like business grade
chips. Not frontier level chips,
business grade chips, RTX 6000. You're
not spending $4 million for a rack.
You're spending 30 grand on an AI
workstation and then you buy like five
of them. Okay, big deal, right? You
could do a lot of compute with that. You
could, that's what we're doing with
reinvest. We could do a lot of damage
and a lot and make a lot of progress
with these workstations. And so then the
question is, okay, so how then does this
affect the entire market? How does this
affect where you want to invest? And so
this is where I got to thinking to
myself, okay, maybe you could invest in
a company like Corsair because if people
are buying workstations, well, great.
people buy workstations, they're going
to need PSUs, they're going to need
motherboards. Sure, they'll need memory
uh and and some of these GPUs, but those
GPUs are lower margin for AMD uh and
Nvidia on those consumer grade products.
So then you think, okay, well, you know,
Corsair kind of packages all of this
together, but I hate to say it, when I
look at the financials for Corsair, they
just had banger earnings. But when you
look at the financials for Corsair,
you're kind of like, uh, they're not the
greatest. Look at them. I'll throw them
up on screen right here. I've got sales
down 2%. Now, in fairness, their gross
profit is up 21%. So, they've got some
growing pricing power here. It's a name
to pay attention to. It's bouncing off a
low, right? I'm not here to bag on it.
I'm actually saying it's bouncing off a
bottom, right?
uh and and they are going to sell AI
workstations, which they do caution
won't be part of their revenue until
like late 2027, but a lot of people are
already selling these stations. They've
only got an 8% net margin. So, they're
really trading for a two peg 13.7 PE
ratio uh or sorry, a 15.2 PE ratio.
Earnings are expected to be 90 cents and
you've got a growth rate of about 7 to
10% of the company. So you're trading
for two peg for an 8% net margin. It's
not great. The balance sheet is okayish
and uh you know they do a free cash flow
of about $98 million. It's a smaller
company you know $ 1.5 billion company
buying back a little bit of the issuance
that they're doing for stock comp and
paying off some debt but these are
little nominal numbers. And so I'm like
ah these layers are commoditized. So you
really have two ways to invest. One way
is the consumer towards enterprise
level, but that's really commoditized.
The other way is memory and edge level
GPUs like the high margin Nvidia chips
or AMD chips. But the problem with that
in my opinion is those guys are heavily
reliant on their valuation or the
valuation of companies like Anthropic.
And based on I I don't know how accurate
this is, but this chart at
stockanalysis.com shows Anthropic stock
valuation has actually come down from a
peak of nearly $1.4 trillion down to
$826 billion. I don't know how accurate
that is, but if that's true, there needs
to be a fire under the butts of Daario
and Sam Alman to IPO as soon as freaking
possible. That way they can raise as
much money as possible, keep blowing
money on that really expensive
artificial intelligence hardware from
Nvidia and AMD and keep the hardware
cycle going. Otherwise, you're going to
end up hitting I mean you're definitely
going to hit a limit. My opinion, okay,
when I say definitely, I want to be
clear that's an opinion. I think
artificial general intelligence is
fugazi. you are going to hit a limit
with artificial intelligence at the way
we know it today. Uh this is a typical
S-curve dynamic. Artificial general
intelligence in my opinion is a lie. It
requires the ability to reason in in
scenarios you haven't seen before. Not
relying on patterns. That's something
that AI today is really bad at. AI today
is really good at patterns and pattern
matching and and linking patterns. In
fairness, you have to adapt knowledge
from one domain and apply it to another.
AI today is not great at doing that. You
have to recognize when you're on the
wrong course. You have to selfrecognize
when you're hallucinating. AI is not
good at that. And you need goal
management to determine when should you
stop, when should you ask for help, when
should you restrategize. AI is not good
at that today. And you have to recognize
when there are practicalities that limit
your AI suggestions, if you will. AI
kind of fails at all of those levels.
And and that's fine. That's not saying
it's bad. It's it's potential. But we're
trying to solve those problems. And what
we're doing is we're, as Michael Sailor
would say, asmmptoically
approaching the limit of technology.
We're approaching the line. This is like
Bitcoin issuance, right? This part right
here. We are asmmptoically approaching
zero. We're asmmptoically approaching
the end of progress to AI. And this is
why these openweight models are catching
up. So damn, Kevin, that is a lot. Too
many big words. Simplify this crap for
me, Kevin. Just tell me what the bottom
line is. Okay, the bottom line,
actually, I have to tell you one more
thing. One more thing before the bottom
line. U
in order for Nvidia to keep all this
crap going, this spending going, it's no
surprise, and I looked at Nvidia's
financials this week, and it's no
surprise that Nvidia is exploding their
investing activity. Most people don't
look at this on the cash flow statement
for Nvidia, but Nvidia is blowing money
into the purchases of non-marketable
securities and marketable debt and
equity securities. $26.5 billion in one
quarter. That is more than they did in
all of 2025, including these investments
into Lancium, uh, NBIS, Marll,
Cororeweave, Intel, Lummentum, Coherent,
Synopsis, Nokia. Why? Because it's
simple. Nvidia invests in these
companies. Those companies buy chips,
which is high margin revenue for Nvidia.
Investors in Nvidia rejoice, and then
there's more cash available to keep the
cycle going. It's circular financing at
its best.
Open AIOropic bottom line might end up
being a tough a peak
in terms of when they IPO for what they
end up doing for AI hardware. Okay,
that's like your peak push potentially
unless Microsoft and Meta and Google
somehow keep this going maybe. Okay,
that's the frontier level side for the
enterprise side. I mean, yeah, there are
companies that put stuff together. I
mean, you could argue AMD's got its
Halo, Nvidia's got the Spark. These are
lower margin products. I don't we don't
find them particularly useful. Apple's
got the mini, right? You could use those
as AI workstations, but lower margins
that makes none of these really
particular desire, really particularly
desirable on a workstation basis. And
you know what's more desirable? There's
the bottom line out of all of it. It's
the companies. And this is why I put my
own hat on. And I'm like, well, like as
as openweight models get cheaper and
cheaper and we could buy this hardware
and do more and more damage with
hardware that's getting us close to
frontier level at a cheaper price, we're
basically taking advantage of this
commodity. And so we're winning in my
opinion as a prop tech startup, you
know, a real estate uh technology
company. So that makes me really
excited. Now, I get that that feels a
little anticlimactic because it's sort
of like, hey, we've been looking at all
these great hardware names, and I still
agree. I still agree that if the second
wave of hardware investment comes the
way I expect it will, it's going to come
from the dumping of SpaceX money, the
dumping of anthropic and open AI money.
I still believe that second wave comes
as a medium-term trade, right? That's
like a six-month opportunity. Still,
Nvidia, Marll, uh, LSCC, some of these
other names, I think they can still do
quite well over that six-month period of
time. But my point is, we're approaching
the limit of the end of that big spend
hardware cycle, and then we're going to
move to the lower margin hardware cycle.
A move from the high margin hardware
cycle to the lower margin hardware
cycle, the more enterprise optimized
cycle is not bullish hardware because
it's commoditized hardware. So let's
let's draw that because you know I saw
this shift to CPUs back when AMD was
like 196 bucks and we talked about it in
the alpha membership. We're like hey
reinvest is buying a lot of CPUs. This
could be an early trade, right? And
people regularly say, "Kevin, man, you
come early all the time." Uh, but my
thinking is if the dollars from the AI
boom have gone into high margin first,
then and those are the beneficiaries of
Nvidia, the memory stocks, Micron,
whatever, all the high margin hardware.
Then naturally as we go into low margin,
people are going to be looking and
going, "Oh, okay. Is that going to be
like a Corsair, you know, your PSU
suppliers, your assemblers, your enter,
you know, your basically your little
computer system put together. That's a
new word. Uh I think the answer to that
is no because there's still low margin
plays. And so the real pricing power is
actually in the survivor
uh software companies.
That's where the money is. And so that's
where the effort has to go is picking
those. Now, you know, I I don't always
like to just do the oh get the full list
over at me.com. You get that? Okay. But
I'll just give an example. We already
know Palanteer is one of those
beneficiaries. Another example would be
like an axon, but there's a lot of
volatility in these. For example, in my
opinion, there was no rationale for
Palunteer to really bleed at all. Yet
that my fundamentals could say, "Hey,
it's actually got a good valuation
around this 130 range." Sure. Would I
like to buy it as a backup the truck at
89? Yes. But our technical analysis, as
you can see, was converging towards this
106 line anyway. And that's why we
bought more exposure to Palanteer before
we ever got uh through 106 because
there's no guarantee you're going to get
to your target, right? The point is to
me there was no fundamental reason to
see a bleed out here when it is actually
one of the major beneficiaries. Another
example of a major beneficiary is a
company like Axon. Now the problem is
it's software. So you get a lot of
volatility. We literally just broke into
this down channel and what a surprise,
we literally rejected the top of that
down channel. I mean, it's almost a
perfect down channel, right?
So with this said, the market isn't of
this mindset yet. Even though we can get
this massive boost in Palunteer stock in
the span of few days, some of that is
going to be trade momentum. I mean, look
at this. We're massively overbought on
the day. If we go to the week, we
literally just went from almost oversold
to overbought in the span of a week,
right? So that this is early and that's
my point with this is this transition
from high margin to low margin hardware
isn't beneficial for hardware at all.
Instead, it's beneficial to software,
but that takes time. And Q3, Q4, I hope,
which is now to the end of the year, is
the beneficiary of that play. Uh, and to
me the fundamentals point in exactly
that direction and it's exactly what
we're seeing at my startup. And again,
we're a propt tech startup, right? So
like we have about, if you include
developments and the real estate we have
at market value, about $100 million of
no bank debt real estate. And with that
foundation, we are also building
our own artificial intelligence suites
for what we're eventually going to call
as a as a terminal. And that's going to
include the housing artificial
intelligence and the stock artificial
intelligence and the algorithms that
we're building to basically take Kevin's
mindset and scale it out to any company
or most importantly any house to
determine, hey, is there a potential
good deal here? Obviously, you still got
to go look under the hood yourself, but
it's a great head start. And so that's
what we're really excited about and
that's what we're seeing as we're
building this company uh piece by piece
every day. We just build build and we're
really excited. Uh and so I feel like
it's my duty to share that with you. Uh
and so if you want to join us and get a
little bit more behind the scenes. Hey,
join us over at meetke.com. We'd love to
have you. Use that special Lauren's
birthday coupon code. Little bonus for
the day and we'll see you in the next
video. Thanks so much for being here.
Goodbye and good luck. Why not advertise
these things that you told us here? I
feel like nobody else knows about this.
>> We'll we'll try a little advertising and
see how it goes.
>> Congratulations, man. You have done so
much. People love you. People look up to
you.
>> Kevin Pra there, financial analyst and
YouTuber. Meet Kevin. Always great to
get your take.